（綱手）今までとは違う。　戦争だ。
This will be a war unlike
any other we've had.
シカマル　お前には前線にて→
Shikamaru, I need you in charge
of the front lines.
司令塔として
働いてもらわねばならない。
（シカマル）はい。
お前の頭脳に期待しているぞ。
Yes, ma'am.
I'm counting on your sharp intellect.
♪～
（シカク）ん？
シカマル　お前の番だ。
Shikamaru, it's your turn.
心ここにあらず。　怖いのか？
Your mind seems somewhere else.
Are you scared?
怖いんじゃねえ。
俺の判断ミスひとつで仲間が死ぬ。
It's not that I'm scared.
If I make one bad decision,
my comrades will die.
何をすればいいか
何ができるのか…。
So what do I do?
What will I be able to do?
迷いもするさ。
I have doubts.
お前も　千日手に
はまっちまったようだな。
You are stuck in Repetition too.
《千日手…。
Repetition...
盤面上の駒の配置
手番　持ち駒の種類や数→
When each player has the same pieces
positioned on the shogi board,
and the same pieces in hand,
まったく同じ状態が４回現れると
その勝負はなかったことになる》
four repeated moves will
force a draw.
目的を見失うな。
ナルトに会ってこい。
Don't lose sight of your goal.
Go see Naruto.
補給任務がある。
え？
There is a supply mission.
ちょうどいい
気晴らしにもなるだろう。
It will be a nice diversion for you.
行ってこい。　お前を推薦しておく。
You should go.
I will recommend you.
ibitsu na merodll de dekita aisareru beki ikimono da
Made from a distorted melody,
I'm a creature that should be loved
seika wa agerarenakute mo kokoro ga utatte iru kara
Even if I can't better myself,
I'll continue to sing from my heart
dore dake tsuyoi ame koete aisareru beki ikimono ka?
What storms must I overcome
To be a creature who should be loved?
yakusoku ga mamorenakute mo kokoro wa utatte iru kedo
Even if you can't keep your promise
My heart will keep on singing, but...
dono doa nokku shite aketara ii?
Which door should I knock on and open?
aketara doko e mukattara ii?
Once I open it, where should I go?
hitori ja kaerenai kara
I can't go home by myself
dareka o matte ita dake
I was just waiting for someone
kimi ga ima ichiban aitai hito wa dare?
Who is the one you want to meet the most?
kokoro no naka de dake hanaseru hito no kazu wa fuete iku
The number of people that I can only speak to in my heart
keep increasing
dakara tsuyoku naritakatta tada
So I just wanted to be strong
bokura mada yomitarinai monogatari
Our story just hasn't been told enough
muriyari owarenai koto wakattete
We know it's not something we can just quit
dare mo mina jibun no mama
Because we all want to be ourselves
tsuyoku naritakatta kara
We wanted to be strong
The Closed Route
（テンテン）静かなところね。
It's so quiet here.
あぁ。　ここ藻屑島は→
Yeah.
The large coral reefs
around Mokuzu Island function
この大きな環礁が
自然の防波堤となり→
as a natural breakwater.
波も穏やかな
理想的な港が作られた。
So the waves are very gentle
and make it an ideal harbor.
えぇ　海なのに　まるで鏡みたい。
Yes, this sea is like a mirror.
の割には…。
Having said that...
♪～
MOKUZU RAMEN
ここに長居は無用だな。
We shouldn't linger here too long.
取り舵いっぱ～い！
Hard-a-port!
（ナルト）フン！　ったく…。
Damn it! Tasting local delicacies
is part of the fun of traveling!
ご当地名物を食うのが
旅の醍醐味だっつうのによ！
もう少しで
日が沈みそうじゃねえか。
The sun's gonna set real soon!
もう　なんで上陸もしねえで
出航すんだよ！
Why do we have to set sail
without even docking?
里の英雄になっても
ナルトって相変わらずね。
He may be the village hero,
but he's still the same old Naruto.
フッ　こんな時に気楽なもんだ。
How can you be so carefree
at a time like this?
何か言ったか！？
Did you say something?
関係ねえよ。　こっちの話だ。
Forget it. It doesn't concern you.
だいたい　おめえらってば
なんで藻屑島で待ってたんだ？
In any case, why were you guys
waiting at Mokuzu Island?
物資の補給だよ。
Replenishing supplies.
物資？
Supplies?
そんなもん　どこにあんだよ！？
So where are they?
（テンテン）ここよ！
Here!
わぁっ！
た…　助けて…。
H-Help.
（アオバ）ほぅ…
歩く倉庫といったところか。
What are you, a walking supply store?
クッ！
大丈夫か？
Are you all right?
見てねえで　お前も助けろよ。
Don't just stand there watching.
Help me.
《ナルトに会っても
答えは見つかんねえよ　親父》
I didn't find the answer by
seeing Naruto either, Dad.
（ヤマト）霧が濃くなったね。
気をつけてくれ。
The fog has gotten thick.
Be careful.
大丈夫です。
羅針盤がありますから。
Don't worry.
We have a compass.
Huh?
おかしいな…。
どうしたんだい？
That's strange.
What's wrong?
《今の俺に　みんなを束ね
その命を預かることができるのか。
Do I really have the power right now
to command everyone
and hold their lives in my hands?
俺は　どうすればいい…》
What should I do?
どうした？　シカマル。
What's the matter, Shikamaru?
ん？
いや…　なんでもねえ。
Oh... it's nothing.
ところで　ガイ先生は　どうした？
姿が見えねえようだが。
By the way, where's Guy Sensei?
I don't see him.
あぁ　海に出てからずっと船酔いで
今も船室で　ひっくり返ってる。
Well, he's been seasick
from the time we set out.
Even now, he's lying down
in his quarters.
（ガイ）みんな　おはよう！
Good morning, everyone!
なんだ　ガイ先生
元気じゃないっすか。
Guy Sensei, you look fine.
よぉ　シカマル　来てたのか。
Shikamaru, you're here!
船が動いてんのに
ほんとに大丈夫なのか？
The ship's moving.
Are you all right?
あぁ！　今日は全然　船酔いしない。
さわやかな目覚めだ。
Yes, I don't feel seasick at all today.
What a great way to wake up.
うぉ～！
一寸先は霧　何も見えんぞ。
The fog is so dense,
I can't see a thing.
って今ごろ気づいたのかよ。
まったく船酔いボケだってばよ。
Did you just notice that?
Seasickness has made you dense—
（２人）うわっ！　わぁ～！！
危ねえ！　影首縛りの術！！
Watch out!
Shadow Strangle Jutsu!
おい！　うわぁ！
助かった…。
面目ない。
That was a close call.
I'm sorry about that.
おい　船のまわりが岩だらけだぞ。
Hey, there are rocks all
around the ship!
この辺りに
岩礁地帯はないはずだが…。
There shouldn't be any
reef systems around here.
しっかり舵を取って！
Hold the rudder steady.
無理です！　避けきれません！
It's useless.
I can't avoid the rocks!
ここは　木ノ葉の燃える青春
マイト・ガイに任せておけ！
You can leave it to me, Might Guy...
The Leaf's Burning Youth!
とぉ～っ！　チェスト～！！
Chesto!
まだまだ！　アチョ～！　アチョ～！
I'm not done yet!
ムチャクチャだ…。
ガイ先生らしいけど…。
He's going wild.
But that's so like Guy Sensei.
ゲキマユ先生　後ろ！　後ろ！
Bushy Brow Sensei,
behind you! Behind you!
え？
Huh?!
うわぁ！
ムムム…　なんの　これくらいの岩！
A rock this size is nothing!
えっ！？
アチョ～！
タァ～ッ！
《クソッ　なんか手はねえのか…》
Damn it.
Isn't there something we can do?
ヤマトさん！
あぁ！
Yamato!
I know!
木遁！
Wood Style!
♪～
うっ…。
大丈夫か？　ヤマト隊長。
あぁ。
Are you all right,
Captain Yamato?!
Yeah.
あれを見て！
Look at that!
でっけえ…　渦潮だ！
なんだって！？
It's a huge whirlpool!
What?!
あんなのに巻き込まれたら
こんな船　ひとたまりもないぞ。
This ship doesn't have a chance
if it's pulled into that thing!
駄目だ！　舵がきかない！
This isn't good.
The rudder's not working!
♪～
どうすんだってばよ！
What are we gonna do?!
ナルト　超大玉螺旋丸だ！
Naruto, use Massive Rasengan!
へ？　超大玉螺旋丸？
What? Massive Rasengan?
いいから　渦に叩き込め！
わ…　わかった！
Never mind! Just hurl one in there!
O-Okay!
ヤマト隊長！　回収しっかり頼むぜ！
Captain Yamato, make sure
you pull me back.
あぁ　任せろ！
You got it.
おりゃ～！
今だ！
クッ！
Now!
（モズク）チッ　しぶてえやつらだ。
They're a tough bunch.
ふぅ…。
これで　もうオーケー？
Are we okay now?
（３人）はぁ…　おっ！？
おっ！？
あ…　これは！
What the—?!
チッ　またか…。
Not again?
この～！　何度でも叩き壊すまで！
Damn it! I'll keep pulverizing
every single one of them!
とぉ～！　チェスト～！
Chesto!
アチョ～！
えっ！？
What?!
ナルト！
あ…　あぁ！
Naruto!
Right!
うぉ～っ！
《何なんだ？　いったい
何が起こってやがる！？
What is this?
What is going on?
自然現象にしては不自然だ。
This is too weird to be
a natural phenomenon.
俺たちの任務は　ナルトを雷の国に
無事届けること。
Our mission is to make sure Naruto
gets to the Land of Lightning safely.
もし　ナルト奪還を目的とする
仕掛けだとすると→
If this is a trick in order
to abduct Naruto,
敵の存在を確認しねえと》
we have to identify the enemy.
なんだと～！？
What?!
くっ！　うぅ…　うわぁ～！
はぁ～っ！
《これで三度目…　敵の目的は
俺たちのチャクラ切れか？
This is the third time.
Is the enemy trying to make
Naruto and the others
use up their chakra?
しかし　いまだ近くに
敵の気配は感じねえ。
But even now, I sense
no presence of the enemy.
これは　幻術か…？》
Could this be a genjutsu?
《いや　あれは実体だ。
あと考えられるのは→
No, that's the real thing.
Or, it could be
the Transportation Technique.
時空間忍術か…　違う！
Nope.
これほど大規模な結界空間を
作れる忍なら→
A shinobi capable of laying down
a massive spatial barrier like this
チャクラ切れなんて　まどろっこしい
手をうつとは思えねえ》
wouldn't need to bother forcing us
to use up our chakra.
もう　チャクラが…。
I'm all out of chakra.
なに！？
What?!
４回目か…　フンッ
まるで　千日手ってとこか？
This is the fourth time.
Just like the Repetition move.
ガイ先生！
Guy Sensei...
無理！　みんなもう　クタクタよ！
It's hopeless!
We've all run out of steam!
だよな…。
I figured as much.
めんどくせえけど…。
This is a drag, but...
もう　俺しかいねえ。
I'm not only one left!
Controlling a vessel
as heavy as a sailing ship
俺の術じゃ　帆船ほどの重量を
コントロールするのは容易じゃねえが。
won't be easy with my jutsu, but...
I have no choice!
やるっきゃねえ！　ん？
シカマル…　お前にそんなこと
期待しちゃいねえ。
Shikamaru, I don't expect
anything like that from you.
What?
なに！？
力仕事は　俺に任せろ。
Leave the physical work to me!
頭を使って　この状況から
脱出する方法を考えんのが→
Your job is to use your head
to figure a way out of this!
おめえの役目だってばよ！
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
♪～
《クソ…　俺は何を焦ってたんだ？
Damn it. Why was I so impatient?
Naruto is absolutely right.
ナルトの言うとおりだぜ》
《もう一度整理しろ。
港を出てから　何があった？
Okay, let's review everything
in order.
What happened after
we left the port?
船は　港を出てすぐに
深い霧の中に入り込み→
As soon as we pulled out of port,
we were surrounded by fog.
ガイ先生は　洋上にもかかわらず
船酔いもせず→
We were on the ocean,
but Guy Sensei didn't get seasick at all.
羅針盤は　あてにならなくなった。
and the compass became unreliable.
しばらくして　岩礁地帯に迷い込み
渦潮が出現した》
Shortly afterwards,
we sailed into a reef system that
was not marked on the sea chart
and a whirlpool appeared.
A whirlpool is caused by
《渦潮は　海底の複雑な地形と
水位差により発生する…》
complex terrain on the ocean bottom
and shifts in sea level.
《しまった！　今日は大潮だ！
Damn it!
Today is a spring tide day!
On top of that, there's only
a narrow entryway to the bay.
しかも　湾には
狭い入り口しかねえ。
A large amount of water flowing in
with the spring tide
そこへ大潮により
大量の海水が流れ込めば→
will easily form a whirlpool.
渦潮は　簡単にできる！
ガイ先生が　船酔いに
ならなかったのも…》
Guy Sensei didn't get
seasick because...
It's such a quiet place.
((テンテン：静かなところね))
the calm waves of that huge bay
held the ship steady.
《あの大きな湾の波の穏やかさが
船の揺れを抑えたんだ。
間違いねえ！》
No doubt about it.
There's a huge rock!
≪大岩だ！
みんな　まとめてかかれ！
Everyone, hold steady!
あれは。
What's that?!
いつの間にこんな印が。
When did that mark appear?
それじゃ
あれは何度もこの船と擦れた跡。
So that means it's from the ship
rubbing against that over and over?
てことは　やっぱり俺たちは→
Which means...
We've been going around
this bay in circles!
湾内をグルグルと
回されてただけってことか。
螺旋丸。
Rasengan!
もうチャクラが。
I've run out of chakra.
There's another huge whirlpool.
また大渦よ。
Another one?!
この～。
もういいんだ　ナルト。
Enough, Naruto. I have an idea.
俺に考えがある。
考えって。
What are you thinking about?
じゃあ俺たちは
どうすりゃいいってばよ。
We'll just sail straight for it
and get swallowed up.
黙ってこのまま渦潮に突っ込んで
のまれりゃいいんだよ。
なに！？
どういうつもりなの　シカマル？
What?!
What on earth are you
up to, Shikamaru?!
テンテン　おめえの力を借りてぇ。
Tenten, I need to borrow your power.
え？
Huh?
フン　藻屑島隠れ名物→
That's what happens
when you get caught
カラクリ仕掛けの魔の海域に
かかればこんなもんだ。
in the Devil's Water Trap
of Mokuzu Island!
They're dead at last!
あいつら
やっとくたばりやがった。
Their ship has been swallowed up
by the giant whirlpool
船は大渦にのみこまれて
海の藻屑だ。
and sent to the bottom of the sea!
よ～し　作戦は完了だ。
（みんな）お～！
All right! Operation over!
– Yay!
– Hurrah!
We have a huge catch today!
今日は大漁だ。
忍のお宝いただこうぜ。
Let's go get our shinobi treasure!
（みんな）お～！
– Yeah!
うん？
なに？　船の破片もないっすよ。
Hey! There's no debris from
the ship floating around!
んだと？　お宝が重すぎて
全部沈んじまったのか？
What? Maybe the treasure was so heavy,
that everything sank.
（みんな）ヘッヘッ。
So every one of you on
Mozuku Island is a thief?
藻屑島ってのは　島民全員が
盗人だってわけか？
てめえは！
Who the hell are you?!
そんなにお宝が欲しけりゃ
腕ずくでとってみな。
If you want our treasure so much,
try and take it away.
Don't be scared!
怯えんな！　やつらは罠を
避け続けて疲れきっているはずだ。
They should be completely exhausted
from dodging the traps!
Don't underestimate shinobi.
忍をナメんな。　テンテン。
えぇ。
– Tenten!
– Right!
なに！？
うわぁ～！
For a trap set by amateurs,
it was pretty clever.
まぁ　素人の罠にしちゃ
上出来だったが　な。
オェ～ッ。　クソッ　また船酔いだ。
Damn it! I'm seasick again!
Shikamaru!
シカマル。
Your sharp intellect
is pretty reliable, after all.
やっぱ　おめえの頭脳は
頼りになるってばよ。
お前に会えてよかったよ。
え？　なんだ？
I'm glad I met you.
Huh? What?
こっちのことだ。
まあいいじゃねえか。
Nothing. Just forget it.
なになに　なに？
教えてくれたっていいだろ。
What, what? Tell me.
What is it?
なぁ　なんだってばよ？
うるせえな。
Shut up, will you?
You're such a pest!
やっぱお前　めんどくせえ
やつだぜ。
なんだと！
What? A pest?!
What do you mean by that?
めんどくせえって
どういうことだってばよ。
Don't just sigh! Tell me!
あ～じゃなくて答えろよ！
あ～？
オェ～ッ。
fight!!
furishiboru dake sa saigo no itteki mo
I'm going to squeeze it down to the last drop
muda ni dekinaikara now is the time to go
Because I can't waste any of it, Now is the time to go
ikudo tsuma tsukimi to egaita yume wa
The dream that I created many times with you
ima koe kuma atte munune o sasu
I can now put it to words and it pierces my heart
it's not crazy
fight and fight, try and try for you
forever
kimi wa hitori janai
You are not alone
namida koete
Get over the tears
kimi to susunde ikou
I'll keep moving forward with you
nani mo kowaku narute na ii na
I'm not afraid of anything
this is the place to try
soshite bokura kitto tsunaida te o
I'm sure we'll never let go
kesshite hanasanaide asu e kakeru
Of each other's hands as we head for tomorrow
let's sing loudly
we are the one for the future
Next Episode
So Barbe-Q's reopening?
Don't worry! I've already made reservations!
Beef tongue with salt, here I come!
They have a special ladies combo on the new menu!
（柴田）皆さ～ん→
It's a good deal! I just can't resist good deals!
大家族　渡津家が
半年ぶりに帰ってきました～！
Frankly, I just love offal!
Hey everyone, did you decide on your drinks?
どんどん成長する子供たちは→
Excuse me! We're ready to order!
相変わらず　元気いっぱい！
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "The Girls' Get-Together"
The Girls' Get-Together
貧しくても　部屋が狭くても→
I'm going to eat my fill today!
いつも　笑顔いっぱいなのが
渡津家なんです。
そして　この半年間→
ほんと～に
いろんな出来事が　ありました。